footsteps?
✓spindash trail? -transparent particles?
✓ camera smoothing again


ideas:
homing attack into a spring cancels momentum, 
just falling onto one does not

✓ ball form: different physuics?

✓ in ball form when leaving ground to air -> stay in ball form while in air

homing attack cancel?

homing attack home in on enemies/object

✓upgrades: bounce bracelet
	cant decide if i want the drop to be a normal move or not


✓"level file" - defines everything in a level
	-model file name
	-collision file name
	-list of objects

✓ fix neutral stick homing attack angle 


slide along walls?
	or at least not make you lose all speed, lose more speed if you are approaching the
	wall perpendicularly
	
	
	
✓ fix sun+sun object+moon position (actually make it go around the sphere and not just that horrible approximation)

add wuhu island level


when underwater, add more friction
	run on water if fast?
	

figure out how the rotation works for line of rings in sadx
	i tried every combination and none worked so idk
	
	try it with negative z rotatino as well - dont forget to try this
	it didnt work

✓collision into chunks

capsule object that stops timer

animating sonics eyes

item capsules

metal sonic model

✓sonic doll playable charcater


challenge: beat emerald coast in under 1:30 to unlock mecha sonic
challenge: beat emerald coast with 350 rings to un;lock sonic doll

add things that can hit you - spikes, rhino thing, crab thing, beetle thing


finally figured out how to rip object models. now i can add palm trees and stuff
	http://info.sonicretro.org/SCHG:Sonic_Adventure_DX:_PC/Model_Locations
	use sadxmdl
	use sonic.exe
	
	write an obj cleaner to parse the generated objs
	
✓add bubbles when splashing

fix friction underwater
	
	
classic sonic has no homing attack, no bounce (maybe has original jump mechanics as well?)

sonic doll has no bounce

metal sonic can ring dash

	make camera follow ring path during ring dash?


✓"buffer time" - time when a level starts when you do not have control and the timer is not running.
screen fades in from black during this, also after restarting from a checkpoint. 
this is for 2 reasons - give player time to take in surroundings before gameplay starts, 
and also to give game time to get things in cache so game doesnt lag at the beginning of gameplay

✓add underwater sections to those two parts in ec, also moving platforms on them
	
	
	
	
✓more goal signs in sand hill

online leaderboard

website

online multiplayer


drop dash - acts like a bounce but you dont bounce
	only avalible on certain characters

chunk system for all of the entities in the gameEntites list, managed by something high up
	would work like the collision chunk system but it would need to be done automatically
	- split objects into chunks when loading, then only call step methods on the 9 closest chunks
	-make sure that the radius of the chunks isnt too small 
	
different homing attack for mecha sonic:
	work like sa2 where it homes in on the enemies and then stops your speed
	
	
rain level
snow level
lower gravity level (moon?)
higher gravity level



